Andrew Gunsch

Phone: (206) 307-7099 Email: andrew@gunsch.cc Web: https://gunsch.cc

Address: 420 Melrose Ave E Apt 501, Seattle, WA 98102

SUMMARY

Building software applications since 2006 with a focus on user-facing products, web application security, and platform engineering. Deep experience with platforms, web applications and cloud-first development. Leading engineering teams since 2014, with a focus on coaching and growing more junior engineers into leaders. Passion for effective communication, relationship-building, and advocating for those most in need.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Engineering, Federal Civilian — Ad Hoc LLC (Remote)

2022 - 2023

- Oversaw engineering delivery in Ad Hoc's growth arm, supporting eleven programs across five federal agencies, plus state and non-profit clients.
- Developed company-wide strategy on platforms, including training materials and best practices for platform engineering, client-facing whitepapers
- Built Content Library for company's institutional knowledge and successes
- Technical SME for Ad Hoc's business development efforts at federal and state agencies, including writing proposals, giving oral presentations, and coding for tech challenges.

Head of Engineering, interim --- Ad Hoc LLC (Remote)

2021

- Oversaw organization of 160+ engineers, spread across a dozen government contracts
- Built out initial structure for engineering organization and community, including:
 - Designed and rolled out a people-management structure across all engineers
 - o Developed company's first engineering career ladder
 - Coordinated volunteers to reinvigorate culture of hackability on internal applications
 - o Created cultural focal points, such as monthly engineering all-hands events
- Identified and led efforts that reduced time-to-hire for engineers by two weeks

Engineering Lead, VA.gov --- Ad Hoc LLC (Remote)

2019 - 2020

- Responsible for delivery of VA's Veteran-Facing Services platform
 - Managed **23 engineers** across 5 sprint teams
 - o Grew VA.gov from a shared codebase into a discrete ecosystem of platform + applications
 - Responsible for application performance, monitoring, 508 compliance, security
 - Provided tooling and support for applications built on VA.gov by 15+ (and growing) teams
 - Directly managing relationships with government client (Digital Experience Product Office)
- Involved in Ad Hoc business development for VA, engineering practices
 - Consultant for VA programs, such as VA APIs (Lighthouse) and VSA (VA.gov applications)
 - o Initial relationship-building and technical analysis for VA Online Scheduling

Staff Software Engineer — Google (Seattle, WA and Mountain View, CA)

2012 - 2019

- Engineering lead for Cloud Endpoints (API Management on Google Cloud) 2018 - 2019
 - Set technical direction for GCP's API management (ten engineers, contributions from 20+).
- Developer Portals for Cloud Endpoints

2016 - 2018

 Launched automatic, hosted developer portals to Endpoints customers. Within weeks of public launch, portals were already being used by majority of active Endpoints customers.

- Collaborated with partners solving similar problems to save them months of dev time.
- Led seven-engineer team (contributions from 15+), setting technical direction and managing the project's schedule and deliverables.
- Promoted to Staff Software Engineer, largely based on this project's delivery. All
 promotion attempts for my team's engineers after public launch were successful.
- Quota Management for Google Cloud Platform

2015 - 2016

- Led six-member project to revamp quota management based on issues identified by user research. User experience for managing quotas was a top user pain point across GCP.
- Chromecast Platform

2014 - 2015

- **Engineering lead** for Cast functionality on Android TV products.
- Focus on HTML5-based media playback (MSE) and content protection (EME)
- o Coordinated solutions across Android teams, hardware OEMs, and content partners.
- Promoted to **Senior Software Engineer** for contributions to this team.
- Search Quality

2012 - 2013

- o Built tools for search analysts to run data experiments across fleets of human raters.
- Overhauled application's security stance and trained peers on web security principles.

Instructional Specialist — The University of Arizona (Tucson, AZ)

Spring 2012

- Constructed curriculum for new, upper-division course on full-stack web development
- Taught initial instance of this class to 120 undergraduates. The class had the highest overall
 Teacher Course Evaluation scores in the Computer Science department for that semester.

Frontend Software Consultant — Self-Employed

2006 - 2011

- Developed custom Uls, features, and third-party integrations for online communities
- Customers typically used vBulletin forum software and LAMP stacks

EDUCATION

University of Arizona (Tucson, AZ)

- B.S.E. in Computer Engineering + B.S. in Computer Science
- Overall GPA: 4.0

AWARDS

- Citizenship Award for infrastructure contributions beyond current role (Google)
- Outstanding Senior in Computer Engineering department (University of Arizona)
- Outstanding Senior in Computer Science department (University of Arizona)
- National Merit Scholar